Guide to the Yale Collection of American Literature Letter Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- "C"
  - CARMAN, BLISS, 1861-1929, 4 (Box 5, Folder 180-183)
    - Compensation. Printer's proof. Poem, of 12 four-line stanzas
    - 1 ALS to Thede [i.e. C(harles) G(eorge) D(ouglas) Roberts?], Boston, Mass., 1907 December 3
      Received with other Roberts material
  - CARNES, FREDERICK G. (Box 5, Folder 184)
    - ALS to Horace P. Chandler, New York, 1862 December 18
      Removed from: his Poems, New York
  - CARPENTER, HENRY BERNARD, 1840-1890 (Box 5, Folder 185)
    - 5 ALS to Charles Marseilles, Boston and Plymouth, N. H., 1887, 1890
      6 leaves
      3 letters are undated
    - ALS to Edward Abbott, Boston, 1882 March 18
    - ALS to "My dear boy" [unidentified], Boston, 1890 February 24
  - CARRYL, CHARLES E. (CHARLES EDWARD), 1841-1920 (Box 5, Folder 186)
    - ALS to Caroline Ticknor, Boston, [1911] October 17
      Removed from: Za copy of his Charades, Boston, 1911
      Alvord fund, November 1943
  - CARRYL, GUY WETMORE, 1873-1904 (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - AL (not signed) on calling card to Edmund Clarence Stedman, New York, 1893 October 8
  - CARY, ALICE, 1820-1871, 2 (Box 5, Folder 188-189)
    - AL in the third person to the Papyrus Club, "Revere House", 1879 February 9
      Declining an invitation
    - ALS to Mr. Williams, 53 East 20th St., [New York], May 10
      Removed from: Za copy of her Poems of Alice and Phoebe Carey... Philadelphia, 1850
    - ALS to J. T. Fields, New York, 1853 September 8
      Removed from: Za copy of her Poems and parodies. Boston, 1854
    - ALS to Mrs. Mary Clemmer Ames, New York, 1864 April 21
      Removed from: Za copy of Ames, A memorial of Alice and Phoebe Cary, N. Y., 1873
    - Alice Cary and the Woman's League. Autograph account written by an unidentified hand
      Removed from: Za copy of Mary Clemmer Ames' A memorial of Alice and Phoebe Cary
    - Dying Hymn. Autograph copy, 5 stanzas
      Removed from: Za copy of her Ballads, lyrics, and hymns. N. Y.,1866
  - CARY, PHOEBE, 1824-1871 (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - Time, the relentless...8 autograph stanzas beginning: Time, the relentless, onward sweeps... Signed, Phoebe Cary
      Removed from: Za copy of Cary, Alice. Poems...Boston, 1855
    - The Fortune in the Daisy. Autograph copy of 10 stanzas signed
      Removed from: Za copy of Ames, The last poems of Alice and Phoebe Cary, N. Y., 1873
    - ALS to an unidentified correspondent, Mt. Healthy, 1851 January 27
  - CASATER, I. A. (Box 5, Folder 191)
    - Canine History of Tantem: mimeographed MS [typescript copy] with a few autograph corrections. Illustrated with photographs
      1 pagel., 14 pages
      From the Estate of Louise R. Pierson, June 1942
  - CATHERWOOD, MARY HARTWELL, 1847-1902 (Box 5, Folder 192)
    - TLS addressed to an unidentified editor, n. p., 1893 July 28
      Gift of Mrs. W. H. Coleman, June 1942
  - CAWEIN, MADISON JULIUS, 1865-1914, 2 (Box 5, Folder 193-194)
    - Elusion. AMS, 9-line poem
    - ALS to James C. Young, Louisville, 1901 July 9
      Plain funds, January 1941
  - CHADWICK, JOHN WHITE, 1840-1904 (Box 5, Folder 195)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Brooklyn, N. Y., 1904 October 31
  - CHANNING, WALTER, 1786-1876 (Box 5, Folder 196)
    - AN to Mrs. E. P. Clark, Boston, 1852 January 1
      Removed from: his New and Old, 1851. Iw.C363.851
      Plain funds, January 1943
  - CHANNING, WILLIAM ELLERY, 1780-1842 (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - Signature clipped from a letter dated from Boston, 1836 November 4
      1 page (mounted)
      Removed from: Aldis copy of his Slavery (1835)
    - ALS to Charles Brooks, Boston, 1841 September
      Removed from: Aldis copy of Poems (1843) by William Ellery Channing, 1818-1901
    - ALS to Barbara [H.] Channing, [n. p.], undated
      Removed from: Aldis copy of Poems, 2d ser. (1847) by William Ellery Channing, 1818-1901
  - CHANNING, WILLIAM HENRY, 1810-1884 (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - ALS to John S. Dwight, Rondout, 1838 September 22
      Includes six of Channing's songs
      Removed from: Za copy of The Present, v.1., no. 1. September. 15, 1843
  - CHAPMAN, MRS. E. S. (Box 5, Folder 199)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Washington, D. C., 1906 August 13
  - CHASE, LEWIS NATHANIEL, 1873-1937 (Box 5, Folder 200)
    - ALS to Karl Young, Rochester, N. Y., 1918 February 15
      Gift of Karl Young
  - CHASE, MARY ELLEN, 1887-1973 (Box 5, Folder 201)
    - ALS to Bernhard Knollenberg, Chicago, [1939] June 22
      Gift of Mr. Knollenberg, June 1939
  - CHILD, FRANCIS JAMES, 1825-1896 (Box 5, Folder 202)
    - ANS to the Hon. C[harles] H[enry] Bell, Cambridge, 1876 September 17
    - 2 ANS to John S. Dwight, Cambridge, [1868, 1868]
      1 page each
  - CHILD, LYDIA MARIA FRANCIS, 1802-1880, 5 (Box 5, Folder 203-207)
    - MS prose quotation, signed and dated, 1878 September
      Plain funds, May 1942
    - 3 miscellaneous MS pieces:
      - Receipt for payment for an article, dated Wayland, 1871 February 11
      - Quotation written for Edward L. Welles, and dated Wayland, 1859 December 22
      - Quotation with signature, undated
    - ALS addressed to "Lucy Ann," Wayland, 1878 June 4
      Removed from: Za copy of her Aspirations of the World, Boston, 1878
    - ALS to Lucretia (Coffin) Mott, Medford, Mass., 1861 February 26
      Plain funds, February 1941
    - 2 ALS to Father Heinrich, 1845
      4 pages each
    - ANS to [James T.] Fields, n. p., circa 1866
    - ANS to Richard P. Hallowell, Wayland, 1879 May 28
    - 2 Autograph MS poems: "Thanksgiving Day" and "June Day instead of May Day"
      4 pages, 4to.
      Removed from: Za copy of her A new flower for children, N. Y., 1856
      Gift of O. F. Aldis, 1911
    - ALS to an unidentified correspondent, New York, 1844 April 23
      2 pages, 4to.
      Removed from: Za copy of her The history of the condition of women, Boston, 1835
    - 5 ALS to John S. Dwight, [n. p.], Wayland, and 7 Groton St., 1846-1877
      Removed from: various Za copies of her books
    - Conclusion of an ALS to her brother, [n. p.], undated
      Removed from: Za copy of her Appeal in favor of Africans, Boston, 1833
    - ALS to Margaret Fuller, [Boston, Mass.?], undated
      Removed from: Aldis copy of L. M. Child's Letters (1883)
    - Parker, Theodore (1810-1860), ALS to Lydia Maria (Francis) Child, Boston, 1855 November 3
      With autograph copy made by Lydia Maria Child, 1 leaf
    - Johnson, Samuel (1822-1882), ALS to Lydia Maria (Francis) Child, n.p., undated.
      Concerns the "Sunset" book
    - Salisbury, Stephen, ALS to Lydia Maria (Francis) Child, Worcester, [Mass.], 1864 November 21
    - May, Samuel J. (1797-1871), ALS to Lydia Maria (Francis) Child, Syracuse, 1855 December 4
      2 leaves (with envelope)
    - Furness, William Henry (1802-1896), ALS to Miss Lucy Osgood, concerning Lydia M(aria) Child's "Progress of religious ideas," n.p., undated
      Removed from: Za copy of Lydia M. Child's "Progress of religious ideas..." N. Y., 1855
    - ALS to Anthony Philip Heinrich, New York, N. Y., 1845 July 22
      [And typewritten copy]
    - The Jews, an autograph copy by L. M. Child of Buckle's Introduction to a History of Civilization
      Removed from: her Progress of Religious Ideas, N. Y., 1855
  - CHILDS, GEORGE WILLIAM, 1829-1894 (Box 5, Folder 208)
    - ALS to Mr. [Frank Henry] Norton, Philadelphia, Pa., 1877 August 13
  - CHURCH, FREDERICK EDWIN, 1826-1900 (Box 5, Folder 209)
    - ALS to Ed S. Rich, New York, 1862 January 10
      Removed from: Theodore Winthrop's A companion to the Heart of the Andes...N. Y., 1859
  - CHURCHILL, WINSTON, 1871-1947 (Box 5, Folder 210)
    - ALS to an unidentified bishop, Newport, R. I., 1907 November 3
      Purchased November. 1966 from R. K. Black; Morse [fund]
  - CIARDI, JOHN, 1916- (Box 6, Folder 211)
    - TLS to Marian King, New York, N. Y., 1960 July 26
      Gift of Marian King, January 13, 1961
  - CLARK, EMILY, 1893-1953 (Box 6, Folder 212)
    - 2 ALS to Charles Parsons, Richmond, Virginia, 1924 April, July
      Gift of Charles Parsons, 1931
  - CLARK, GEORGE H. (GEORGE HENRY), 1819-1906 (Box 6, Folder 213)
    - ALS to George Pope Morris, Hartford, 1853 December 23
      Removed from: The Knickerbocker Gallery, 1855
  - CLARK, JAMES G. (JAMES GOWDY), 1830-1897 (Box 6, Folder 214)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Helena, Mont., 1887 August 20
  - CLARK, WILLIS GAYLORD, 1808-1841 (Box 6, Folder 215)
    - ALS to Morton McMichael, "Thursday," [n. p.], December 24]
      With address leaf
  - CLARKE, EDNAH PROCTOR (Box 6, Folder 216)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Washington, D. C., 1894 March 2
  - CLARKE, J. EDWARDS (Box 6, Folder 217)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Washington, D. C., 1897 January 19
      Removed from: copy of An Opal: Verses...1896 by Ednah Proctor Clarke
  - CLARKE, JAMES FREEMAN, 1810-1888 (Box 6, Folder 218)
    - ALS, Jamaica Plain, Mass., 1884 October 14
      Mounted on sheet with portrait
      Gift of James H. Penniman, May 3, 1921
    - ALS to Mrs. Theodore Parker, Boston Public Library, 1881 March 26
      With addressed envelope
      Removed from: Za copy of O. W. Holmes. Memorial of his 50th birthday, Boston, 1860
  - CLEGHORN, SARAH NORCLIFFE, 1876-1959 (Box 6, Folder 219)
    - TLS to John Farrar, Philadelphia, 1949 December 8
      Gift of John Farrar, 1950
  - CLEMENS, CLARA (Box 6, Folder 220)
    - TLS to Mr. Babb, Hollywood, Calif., 1943 February 6
      Enclosing photograph of Ossip Gabrilowitsch
  - CLEMMER, MARY, 1839-1884 (Box 6, Folder 221)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Washington, D. C., 1883 March 10
  - CLEVELAND, H. W. S. (HORACE WILLIAM SHALER), 1814-1900 (Box 6, Folder 222)
    - ALS to E(dmund) C(larence) Stedman, Minneapolis, Minn., 1888 October 23
      Removed from: his Social Life and literature...Boston, 1888
  - CLEVELAND, LUCY (Box 6, Folder 223)
    - 2 ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, New York; [New York], [1893, 1894]
      2 leaves with 1 envelope
  - CLEVELAND, ROSE ELIZABETH, 1846-1918 (Box 6, Folder 224)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, n.p., 1887 December 4
  - COATES, FLORENCE EARLE, MRS., 1850-1927, 2 (Box 6, Folder 225-226)
    - 2 ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Germantown, Pa., 1897, 1904
    - Autograph verse signed, undated
      Removed from: her Mine and Thine, Boston and New York, 1904 Iy.C306.904
      Southworth fund, October 1947
  - COBB, IRVIN S. (IRVIN SHREWSBURY), 1876-1944 (Box 6, Folder 227)
    - ALS to W(illard) H(untington) Wright, New York, N. Y., circa 1913
  - COBB, SYLVANUS, 1823-1887 (Box 6, Folder 228)
    - ALS to "Dear Robert," Hyde Park, Mass., 1874 August 28
      Possibly to Robert U.? Johnson
  - COBLENTZ, STANTON ARTHUR, 1896- (Box 6, Folder 229)
    - TLS to Professor William Lyon Phelps, Mill Valley, Calif., 1942 March 23
      Removed from: his Winds of Chaos, N. Y., 1942
      Gift of Mr. Phelps, January 1943
  - COCKE, ZITELLA, 1840-1929 (Box 6, Folder 230)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Boston, [1898] June 8
      1 leaf (4 pages) with envelope
      Removed from: her A Doric reed, Boston, 1895.
  - COFFECEN, CARRIE (Box 6, Folder 231)
    - Draft of letter to Nathaniel Parker Willis, Cornwall-on-the-Hudson, 1857 [with note by James T. Babb, December. 26, 1946]
      Gift of James T. Babb, December 1946
  - COFFIN, ROBERT BARRY, 1826-1886
    See: GRAY, BARRY, 1826-1886
  - COHAN, GEORGE M. (GEORGE MICHAEL), 1878-1942, 2 (Box 6, Folder 232-233)
    - The Farrell Case, Typescript (carbon)
      1-act play
      17 leaves
    - The Great Hollywood Plot. Typewritten ms signed in pencil and with ms corrections
      Gift of Professor Jack R. Crawford,
      February 1951
  - COLLIER, THOMAS S. (THOMAS STEPHENS), 1842-1893 (Box 6, Folder 234)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, New London, Conn., 1890 January 4
      Removed from: Za copy of his Song spray...New London, Conn., 1889
  - CONWAY, MONCURE DANIEL, 1832-1907 (Box 6, Folder 235)
    - ALS to "Dear Sir" [unidentified], London, 1877 January 24
    - ALS to Miss Miller, Boston, Mass., [1889]
      Concerning a lecture that he will give in Washington, D. C.
      Letter states lecture will be "near the centennial of Washington's first Inauguration"
    - ALS to "Dear Sir," Washington, D. C., 1887 December 16
      Concerning letters of Weedon in the possession of his correspondent
    - ALS to unidentified recipient, London, 1895 May 28
      Gift of James M. Osborn, August 1953
    - ALS to Edwyn Ashworth, London, 1897 March 29
    - ALS to Thomas Wentworth Higginson, Turham Green [London], 1882 May 22
      [With photocopy]
      Purchased on the Alvord Fund,
      September 1953
    - ALS to Mr. Morse, New York, 1888 March 22
  - COOK, JOSEPH, 1838-1901 (Box 6, Folder 236)
    - Autograph quotation signed, Boston, Mass., 1883 October 1
  - COOK, KENINGALE, 1845-1886 (Box 6, Folder 237)
    - ALS to [H(arry) Buxton Forman], Highgate, N. [England], 1873 April 20
      3 pages on 1 leaf
      Gift of Adrian Van Sinderen
      Removed from: Forman's Music and poetry...London, 1872
  - COOKE, JOHN ESTEN, 1830-1886 (Box 6, Folder 238)
    - ALS to Frank M(arx) Etting, Millwood, Va., 1876 June 24
    - ALS to his father, John Rogers Cooke, Martinsburg, 1850 July 21
  - COOKE, PHILIP PENDLETON, 1816-1850 (Box 6, Folder 239)
    - ALS to Messrs. Carey and Hart (Carey, firm, publishers, Philadelphia; 1847: Carey and Hart), The Vineyard, near Millwood, Clarke County, Va., 1847 April 29
      Concerns the sale of his Froissart ballads
  - COOKE, ROSE TERRY, 1827-1892, 3 (Box 6, Folder 240-242)
    - Oasis. AMS. Poem of six 4-line stanzas
    - 6 ALS to B. H. Ticknor, Winsted, Conn., 1886-1888
      Removed from: Za copy of her Steadfast, Boston, 1889
    - ANS to Messrs. J. R. Osgood and Co., Winsted, Conn., 1881 February 3
      Removed from: Aldis collection of autographs
    - ALS to an editor of the Atlantic Monthly [probably James Russell Lowell], Hartford, Conn., 1857 November 26
      Submitting her story "Eben Jackson"
      [Gift of Owen F. Aldis, 1911; in his coll. of autographs]
    - ANS to Edward William Bok, Winsted, Conn., 1887 July 14
      Removed from: Za copy of her Poems, Boston, 1861
    - ALS to an unidentified correspondent, Winsted, Conn., 1877 October 13
    - 3 ALS to Benjamin H. Ticknor, Winsted, Conn., 1885-1886
      Removed from: her The Sphinx's Children, Boston, 1886
    - ANS to B. H. Ticknor, Winsted[, Conn.], 1887 January 3
      Removed from: Za copy of her A Lay Preacher, Boston, 1884
    - ALS to Miss Homes [?], Winsted, Conn., 1885 July 15
    - ALS to Mr. (James Ripley) Osgood, Winsted, Conn., 1881 September 1
      Reporting no progress on a novel
  - COOPER, GEORGE, 1840-1927 (Box 6, Folder 243)
    - Sweet Genevieve (1869), AMS with author's note: "Written and published in 1869-"
      1 leaf in [ms] case
      Poem of 2 eight-line stanzas, each followed by 5-line refrain. Without the music. Leaf is folded
      Gift of Mrs. Richard Gimbel, 1974
  - COPPEE, HENRY, 1821-1895 (Box 6, Folder 244)
    - ALS to Mr. Allibone, Bethlehem, Penn., 1883 December 7
      The signature and Mr. Allibone's name only are in Coppee's autograph
    - ANS to Jesse C. Green, Bethlehem, Penn., 1886 March 19
      Including autograph poem: Christmas echoes signed "H. C."
  - COURNOS, JOHN, 1881-1966 (Box 6, Folder 245)
    - ALS to Harry Preller, New Haven, Conn., 1927 June 30
      Gift of Mrs. H. A. Preller, 1952
  - COWAN, FRANK, 1844-1905 (Box 6, Folder 246)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Greenesburgh, Pa., 1892 February 17
  - COX, KENYON, 1856-1919, 2 (Box 6, Folder 247-248)
    - Autograph cut from a letter and mounted on a sheet
      1 leaf [mounted]
      Transferred from Ms Vault, February 1973
    - ALS to Charles Elmer Rice, New York, N. Y., 1912 February 28
      Purchased on Library Associate funds, January 1973
  - CRANCH, CHRISTOPHER PEARSE, 1813-1892 (Box 6, Folder 249)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Cambridge, Mass., 1885 October 24
      Removed from: Za copy of his The bird and the bell...Boston and N. Y., 1890
    - ALS to John S. Dwight, Paris, 1856 December 30
      With postscript added January 4, 1857
      Removed from: Za copy of his The bird and the bell...Boston, 1875
    - ALS to John S. Dwight, Paris, 1855 May 16
      Aldis collection of autographs
    - ALS to William J. Bok, Cambridge, Mass., 1890 October 20
      Removed from: Za copy of his Kobboltozo...Boston, 1857
    - ALS to Miss Bates, Matteawan, N. Y., 1886 September 10
      Removed from: Za copy of his The Aeneid of Virgil translated into English blank verse...Boston, 1872
      [Miss Bates became Miss Roge]
  - CRANDALL, CHARLES HENRY, 1858- (Box 6, Folder 250)
    - 2 ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Springdale, Conn., 1889, 1894
    - The School Teacher, a poem, [n. p.], undated
      Clipping mounted with ms corrections
      Removed from: his The chords of life ...Springdale, Conn., 1898
  - CRANE, CORA HOWORTH (TAYLOR) [MRS. STEPHEN CRANE] (Box 6, Folder 251)
    - 19 ALS (five undated) to G. H. Perris, South Kensington, London, and New Orleans, 1900-1901
      Together with typewritten copies of these letters
      Gift of Mr. and Mrs. H. B. Vanderpoel, December. 1941
    - Richards, Grant (1872-1948). TLS to G. H. Perris, London, 1900 December 4
      Gift of Mr. and Mrs. H. B. Vanderpoel, December 1941
    - Typewritten copy of an agreement between Stephen Crane and Methuen and Co. for publication of the English edition of his novel, The O'Ruddy, dated, 1899 July 12
      Gift of Mr. and Mrs. H. B.
      Vanderpoel, December. 1941
    - 3 ALS to Edward Garnett, Ravensbrook, 1899 January 10, 19
      1 undated
      6 pages with two envelopes
      With note from Miss Alice Beer, 1948 April 12
  - CRANE, ELIZABETH GREEN (Box 6, Folder 252)
    - ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Scarsdale, N. Y., 1903 February 2
  - CRANE, STEPHEN, 1871-1900, 2 (Box 6, Folder 253-254)
    - ALS to Edward Garnett, Ravensbrook, November 16
      With letter from Miss Alice Beer to Mr. J. T. Babb, 1 page, Sept. 5, 1947
      Gift of Miss Alice Beer, October 1947
    - TLS to Dr. Charles J. Little, Brede Place, Brede, Northiam, Sussex, England, 1899 February 6
      With envelope addressed in Crane's hand
      Gift of Mrs. William H. Dunham, 1948
  - CROFFUT, W. A. (WILLIAM AUGUSTUS), 1835-1915 (Box 6, Folder 255)
    - 2 ALS to Edmund Clarence Stedman, Washington, D. C., 1896 May 1, 6
  - CROSS, WILBUR L. (WILBUR LUCIUS), 1862-1948, 2 (Box 6, Folder 256-257)
    - TL (carbon copy) to John Hall Wheelock, 1936 September 3
      Bequest of Wilbur Cross, 1948
    - Radio message to the people of Conn. Negative photostat. Delivered at 3 A.M., November 9, 1938, the morning after the election of Raymond Baldwin as Governor
    - ALS and TLS to the Yale University Library, Burkehaven, N. H. and New Haven, Conn., 1929 July, October
      With carbons of five replies Concerning books borrowed from the Library
  - CUMMINGS, E. E. (EDWARD ESTLIN), 1894-1962 (Box 6, Folder 258)
    - 1 TLS and 2 TPCS to James T(inkham) Babb, New York, N. Y., [1952], 1958
      With 2 TL (carbons) from Mr. Babb to Mr. Cummings
      Concerning the Bollingen prize in poetry of the Yale University Library
  - CURTIS, GEORGE WILLIAM, 1824-1892, 6 (Box 7, Folder 259-264)
    - ALS to unidentified correspondent, New York, N. Y., 1853 December 31
    - ALS to [George W.] Greene, North Shore, S[taten] I[sland], 1865 June 2
    - ALS to "My dear Madame," Ashfield, Mass., 1877 October 6
      Removed from: Za copy of his Nile notes...N. Y., 1856
    - ALS, Ashfield, Mass., 1871 August 31
      Removed from: Za copy of his Prue and I...N. Y., 1856
    - ALS to "My dear Miss," Staten Island, 1856 November 24
    - ANS to E. P. Whipple, New York, 1855 March 9
      Introducing a Mr. O'Connor
      Removed from: Za copy of his The public duty of educated men, the oration...Albany, N. Y., 1878
    - Fragment, last page, of a letter, [n. p.], undated
      Removed from: Za copy of An oration on the annals of Rhode Island...N. Y., 1863
    - ALS, Staten Island, N. Y., 1879 December 29
      Removed from: Za copy of Description of the ceremony of dedication of the statue of Major-general John Sedgwick
      ...N. Y., 1869
    - ANS to "Dear Madame," Ashfield, Mass., 1880 August 9
      Removed from: Za copy of his From the easy chair...N. Y., 1892, v. 1
    - 2 ANS, Ashfield, Mass., 1870, 1875
      Removed from: Za copy of his Literary and social essays...N. Y., 1894
    - 2 ALS to Professor Botta, Boston and New York, 1870 December 13, 30
      Removed from: Za copy of The Unity of Italy, the American celebration, N. Y., 1871
    - ALS to Mr. Bullen, Ashfield, Mass., 1869 July 3
      Removed from: Za copy of his Lotus-eating...N. Y., 1856
    - ALS to W. W. Caldwell, New York, 1857 September 19
      Removed from: Za copy of his Potiphar papers...N. Y., 1856
    - ANS to Calvin G. Child, North Shore, N. Y., 1861 November 1
      Kingsley Trust Association, November 1945
    - ALS to Henry C. Dorr, Brook Farm, West Roxbury, 1842 May 18
      Gift of Frank Mauran, Jr., May 1940
    - ALS to [J. T.] Fields, Newport, 1855 August 13
      Removed from: Za copy of his Lotus eating...N. Y., 1852
    - ALS to Richard Watson Gilder, Staten Island, N. Y., 1884 November 22
      Removed from: Za copy of his Potiphar papers...N. Y., 1853
    - ALS to Edwin L(awrence) Godkin, Staten Island, N. Y., 1881 May 10
      Removed from: his The progress of reform...N. Y., 1883
    - ALS to Mr. Harrison, Ashfield, Mass., 1882 August 10
      Removed from: Za copy of the Correspondence of Carlyle and Emerson...Boston, 1883
    - ALS to Mr. Ide, North Shore, Staten Island, 1863 October 11
      Removed from: Za copy of his Nile notes...N. Y., 1851
    - ALS to W. J. Linton, Ashfield, Mass., 1875 August 4
      Removed from: Za copy of The Proceedings at the dedication of the soldiers monument...Pittsfield, Mass., 1872
    - ANS to Mr. Tenney, Staten Island, N. Y., 1870 June 23
      Removed from: Za copy of his Ars recti vivendi...N. Y., 1898
    - ALS to Rev. Dr. Thompson, Staten Island, 1864 March 8
      Removed from: Za copy of his Washington Irving...N. Y., 1891
    - ALS to Bayard Taylor, North Shore, 1860 September 6
      Removed from: Za copy of his Trumps...N. Y., 1861
    - ALS to Whipple, N. Y., 1860 April 23
    - ALS to E. P. Whipple, Ashfield, Mass., 1869 September 19
      Removed from: Za copy of his Orations and addresses...N. Y., 1894
    - ALS to Mr. Kendrick, Staten Island, N. Y., 1891 February 21
    - ALS to R. C. Winthrop, Staten Island, N. Y., 1881 November 25
      Removed from: Za copy of his Duty of an American scholar to politics...N. Y., 1856
    - ALS to Mr. Norell, Staten Island, N. Y., 1875 June 14
    - ALS to J. M. Carson, New York, 1860 October 19
      Concerning an invitation to lecture
      Transferred from RBR
      Removed from: Nicolay and Hay's Abraham Lincoln
    - Autograph, 1873 October 27
    - ALS to Mr. Davenport, Ashfield, Mass., 1881 July 18
      2 pages Gift of James T. Babb, 1959
    - ALS to "Dear Sir," New York, N. Y., 1859 March 2
      Concerning arrangements to lecture
    - ALS to "My dear Sir," Ashfield, Mass., [1871] August 6
    - TLS to "My dear Sir," Ashfield, Mass., 1886 September 2
      On politics
    - ALS to George E. Brown, West New Brighton, S[taten] I[sland], N. Y., [1874] March 13
      Declining an invitation to lecture
    - ALS to James T(homas) Fields, New York, N. Y., 1863 July 6
    - ALS to Miss Hudson, Staten Island, N. Y., 1866 March 15
    - ALS to "My dear Potts [?]," Ashfield, Mass., 1881 September 25
      On the death of (U. S.) President (James Abram) Garfield
    - ALS to Mr. Powell, West New Brighton, S[taten] I[sland], N. Y., 1876 November 28